<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed
  xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
  xml:lang="en"
   >
  <title type="text">ambestengestern.de</title>
  <subtitle type="text">ich</subtitle>

  <updated>2011-10-19T19:45:31Z</updated>
  <generator uri="http://blogofile.com/">Blogofile</generator>

  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.ambestengestern.de/blog" />
  <id>http://www.ambestengestern.de/blog/feed/atom/</id>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.ambestengestern.de/blog/feed/atom/" />
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name></name>
      <uri>http://www.ambestengestern.de/blog</uri>
    </author>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Next Steps for the German Software Craftsmanship Community]]></title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.ambestengestern.de/blog/next-steps-for-the-german-software-craftsmanship-community" />
    <id>http://www.ambestengestern.de/blog/next-steps-for-the-german-software-craftsmanship-community</id>
    <updated>2011-09-03T09:32:31Z</updated>
    <published>2011-09-03T09:32:31Z</published>
    <category scheme="http://www.ambestengestern.de/blog" term="sc" />
    <category scheme="http://www.ambestengestern.de/blog" term="conference" />
    <category scheme="http://www.ambestengestern.de/blog" term="socrate2011" />
    <category scheme="http://www.ambestengestern.de/blog" term="softwarecraftsmanship" />
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Next Steps for the German Software Craftsmanship Community]]></summary>
    <content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ambestengestern.de/blog/next-steps-for-the-german-software-craftsmanship-community"><![CDATA[<div style="float:right; margin:20px 0 15px 15px;">
<img src="http://socrates2011.pbworks.com/f/SoCraTesWappen.png" width="200" height="200" alt="Logo of 'SoCraTes'' conference" title=""SoCraTes Logo""/>
</div>

<p>I spent the last one-and-a-half days at the <a href="http://socrates2011.pbworks.com/">SoCraTes</a> conference. I'm still kind of stoked about all the great people I met and were able to talk. It's such a great feeling to be part of such a clever and diverse community. Thanks to <a href="https://twitter.com/NicoleRauch">Nicole</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/leiderleider">Andreas</a> and all the others to make this event happen.</p>
<h3 id="fishbowl_discussion_at_socrates">Fishbowl Discussion at SoCraTes</h3>
<p>I'll certainly talk/blog more about SoCraTes and Software Craftsmanship in general on this blog in the next weeks and months. But for now, I want to summarize the outcome (if you can say, there was one) of the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fishbowl_(conversation)">Fishbowl discussion</a>, that was taking place on Friday evening, the conference's first day.</p>
<p>The discussion started with <a href="https://twitter.com/leiderleider">Andreas</a> , <a href="https://twitter.com/ade_oshineye">Ade</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/urilavi">Uri</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/mgaertne">Markus</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/sandromancuso">Sandro</a>. For the uninitiated, I might add, that Sandro and Uri both started very successful Software Craftsmanship communities in their respective cities.</p>
<h3 id="next_steps">Next Steps</h3>
<p>The first question was (paraphrased) "what are the next concrete steps, to get the Software Craftsmanship community in germany off the ground". And although the question was not answered in a definitive way by anyone throughout the whole discussion, there were a lot of possible steps, tips &amp; tricks shared, that I want to note down as a reference. Note that I might paraphrase one or the other in order to better convey the point (or at least the point that I understood):</p>
<ol>
<li><em>"Find people who are committed to run the groups"</em><br />
This is kind of obvious to most, but still the first and most important point there is to actually starting the communities. Period.</li>
<li><em>"Focus on small geographical areas"</em><br />
We do not and should not aim to build geographical disperse communities/groups. So this is almost abvious. Go for the people in your vicinity, in your city. This does not mean, that you cannot cooperate with groups in other cities, like visiting "partner-groups" regularly or organizing joint-events every now and then.</li>
<li><em>"Define what's not included"</em><br />
<a href="https://twitter.com/ade_oshineye">Ade</a> brought this one up, which generally falls under the category of "expectation management". But putting it in these exact words is so much more tangible and to the point.</li>
<li><em>"Talk about basic principles and skills first (in the meetings)"</em><br />
This was <a href="https://twitter.com/urilavi">Uri</a>'s suggestion. I think this is meant to fulfill the "Raising the bar" tagline of the Software Craftsmanship Manifesto quickly and demonstrate to attendee's of community meetings, that it's not about talk &amp; discussion only.</li>
<li><em>"Promote to people outside the normal groups"</em><br />
I can't remember anymore who said it, but it sure is a way to make sure, that a Software Craftsmanship community/group is not just like any other tech-specific group. Software Craftsmanship groups should aim to encompass a broader goal. It's not about technology <em>xyz</em>, but about pushing boundaries, getting better at what we do.</li>
<li><em>"Work with other local communities // cross-promote events"</em><br />
Which boils down to: Be a good &amp; respectful "citizen". Don't try to "steal" members, but rather work together to foster great communities, not just one great community.</li>
<li><em>"Put limits on how many people are coming"</em>
This is not a next step or tip per se. It was meant as advice for a later stage, when meetings <em>may</em> get out of hand (with regards to size &amp; scope) and is meant to be used in conjunction with point 3. above.</li>
</ol>
<h3 id="what_i_think_are_next_steps">What I think are next steps:</h3>
<p>It was decided during the Fishbowl on Friday evening, that a session would be held during the conference's <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Open_Space_Technology">Open Space</a> on saturday, in which concrete next steps on how to start/launch the Software Craftsmanship community in germany would be decided.<br />
</p>
<p>However, I was not able to attend the conference's second day. So I decided to contribute to this Open Space session from afar and put forth the next actions, that are necessary and sensible from my point of view:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Create a mailinglist for group organizers</strong>, to allow for event coordination and exchange of ideas, tips, tricks &amp; motivation. Everybody who joins this mailinglist declares to organize a new or support an existing Software Craftsmanship group in his/her german city.</li>
<li><strong>Have at least 2-3 Software Craftsmanship groups across germany</strong> by December 2011.<br />
<a href="https://twitter.com/sshishkin">Sergey</a> proposed that the <a href="http://blog.coderetreat.com/global-day-of-coderetreat">Global Day of CodeRetreat</a> would be a good setting for promoting the forming of Software Craftsmanship groups. (this also aligns perfectly with my plan to organize a <a href="http://www.coderetreat-rhein-main.com/">CodeRetreat in Frankfurt or Rhein-Main area</a>, so I might be biased)</li>
</ul>
<p>That's already it. From there on, the local group initiators/organizers will have to organize and promote their groups. And this of course will depend on the local circumstances. But the mailing-list can serve as a back-up for all group leaders to work together and support each other.</p>
<h3 id="talk_to_me">Talk to me</h3>
<p>Want to discuss this article, or how to promote Software Craftsmanship in germany? Contact me on <a href="https://twitter.com/benjamin">Twitter</a> or via <a href="/about.html">email</a></p>]]></content>
  </entry>
</feed>
