<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed
  xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
  xml:lang="en"
   >
  <title type="text">ambestengestern.de</title>
  <subtitle type="text">ich</subtitle>

  <updated>2011-10-19T19:45:31Z</updated>
  <generator uri="http://blogofile.com/">Blogofile</generator>

  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.ambestengestern.de/blog" />
  <id>http://www.ambestengestern.de/blog/feed/atom/</id>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.ambestengestern.de/blog/feed/atom/" />
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name></name>
      <uri>http://www.ambestengestern.de/blog</uri>
    </author>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Project Idea: Learning to Read Code]]></title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.ambestengestern.de/blog/project-idea--learning-to-read-code" />
    <id>http://www.ambestengestern.de/blog/project-idea--learning-to-read-code</id>
    <updated>2011-06-09T09:24:36Z</updated>
    <published>2011-06-09T09:24:36Z</published>
    <category scheme="http://www.ambestengestern.de/blog" term="code" />
    <category scheme="http://www.ambestengestern.de/blog" term="projects" />
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Project Idea: Learning to Read Code]]></summary>
    <content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ambestengestern.de/blog/project-idea--learning-to-read-code"><![CDATA[<p>... with the help of <a href="/projects/fibel.html">Fibel</a>.</p>
<h3 id="idea">Idea</h3>
<p>Imagine a webapp at which you can throw nearly every github or bitbucket repo URL, and it will render the code found in the repo with the help of <a href="http://jashkenas.github.com/docco/">docco</a>, <a href="http://rtomayko.github.com/shocco/">shocco</a> or any other tool with a similar feature set.<br />
</p>
<p>Added Bonus:</p>
<ul>
<li>Allow the creation of "tours" through code, so a user can show off certain features or solutions, in order to aid in the understanding of the code or specific programming constructs.</li>
<li>Allow the annotation of the code trough the webapp, and the code is reflected back to a forked edition of the original repo (which might serve as a basis for a documentation enhancing pull-request).</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="why">Why?</h3>
<p>I've been thinking a lot about what makes a good programmer and how to get there. For quite some time already. Which is not very surprising, when you consider, that my job as a teamlead consists (not only, of course) of evaluating potential candidates and further developing the current team members.</p>
<p><a href="http://manifesto.softwarecraftsmanship.org/">Software</a> <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Software_craftsmanship">Craftmanship</a> is what comes to mind. But also concepts like Code Katas, Code Retreats (I will attend the <a href="http://www.coderetreat-berlin.de/">Code Retreat Berlin</a> in July, but more on that in another post) etc etc.</p>
<p>The one thing however, that I thought about how to solve best, was "reading good code" as a means of getting a feel how to solve problems "the right way" and the idioms and "culture" of a programming language. And as a <a href="https://convore.com/python/examples-of-good-python-code/">thread on convore</a> lately indicates, I'm not the only one thinking about this.<br />
And as I'm looking for a <a href="/projects.html">sensible project to implement</a> I thought that this would be a good direction for a project.</p>
<p>We'll see where I take this idea in the upcoming weeks. I nevertheless added it to my <a href="/projects.html">projects list</a> and dubbed it <a href="/projects/fibel.html">Fibel</a> (which is the <a href="http://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fibel_(Schulbuch)">common name</a> for the first reading book children get in german elementary schools).</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
</feed>
